Grand Rapids, MI 616.405.0409 | kdbomhof@gmail.com

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Software developer who is passionate about the software he writes, and systems he architects. A personal advocate for keeping code testable, and actually tested.

Kyler has professional experience with full-stack development, leading teams, and utilizing the Scrum framework.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Internship

May 2023 - Aug 2023

Auto-Owners Insurance

- Developed full-stack applications aimed at alleviating the burden of labor-intensive maintenance tasks performed by agents.
- Following my work's implementation, agents realized significant time savings, allowing them to allocate more time to acquiring new business.
- Adhered to the Scrum framework while collaborating with a team of business analysts, quality assurance engineers, architects, and other software developers.
- Personally responsible for front-end and back-end architectural decisions, as well as their implementation. Primarily utilized React.js, TypeScript, Node.js, Jest and SQL Server.

Information Technology Internship

May 2022 - Apr 2023

Haworth

- Collaborated with members of the Information Security team to roll out new security software to over 7,000 devices.
- Employed tools like Microsoft Endpoint and Configuration Manager to efficiently deploy application fixes and collect various hardware and software metrics.
- Implemented solutions streamlining IT Administrators' tasks, such as allowing clients to set their own desktop background using Microsoft's Power Platform, saving developers time and improving client experience.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

kylerbomhof.com July 2023 - Present

- A custom mobile-centric website that highlights my skills, experience, and projects.
- Built with cutting-edge rendering technologies, such as React server components, to decrease the initial page load and bundle size. Directly contributing to a more inclusive and improved user-experience.
- Developed using Next.js, styled with Tailwind CSS and DaisyUI. Currently hosted on Vercel.

typetest-cli June 2023 - Present

- A lightweight type speed tester for the terminal, written in Python.
- Published publicly on PyPI and easily installable using pip on any machine capable of running Python.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, TypeScript, Golang, JavaScript/Node.js, Bash, C, C++, Ruby, Java, Lua, PowerShell

Web Development: React.js, Express.js, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, HTML5, CSS/SCSS, Material UI, DaisyUI

CI/CD: Jenkins, Docker, GitHub Actions, Vercel, AWS

Data Management/Data Services: SQL, MySQL/MariaDB, SQL Server, REST, OpenAPI

Testing: pytest, Jest, Cypress, Selenium

System/Development Tools: Linux, Vim, tmux, Bash Scripting, AWK

Version Control/Project Management: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, Scrum, Agile methodologies

EDUCATION

Michigan Technological University

 $Aug\ 2020$ - $Dec\ 2023$

Bachelor of Science - B.Sc, Computer Science

- It Oxygen Team Lead. Using machine learning to categorize enterprise data, allowing the client to determine manufacturing faults before they reach the market, saving thousands in potential recall costs.
- University Innovation Fellows member. Following Agile methodologies while making campus a better place.
- 3.65 GPA